<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on Social Data Science 2021</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on Social Data Science 2021</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workshop 1 - AirBnb revisited</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/01_workshop1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/01_workshop1/</guid><description>Introduction Context: Flashback to AirBnb Data that we used in Workshop 3 of M1 In this workshop we are going to explore the insideairbnb using deep learning techniques. We used the data in a research project some years ago and you can check out a conference presentation below:
1. Build a neural net for price prediction. Your job is to build a feed-forward network using Keras to predict the price. Can you beat the performance of other models that we explored in M1 (using the same set of independent variables)?</description></item><item><title>Workshop 2 - Fun with Timeseries</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/02_workshop2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/02_workshop2/</guid><description>Introduction Context: LSTMS and timeseries You have so far seen how RNNs are used for simle time series. In this workshop we will extend this to multi-step and simultaneusely multi-feature and multi-step situations. Today we are going to make some money 💸 1 We will be using financial data for that. There will be no time for backtesting however.
1. Build a baseline LSTM Build an LSTM net that predicts closing price changes 1 day ahead</description></item><item><title>Workshop 3 - Advanced applicaions and wrap-up</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/03_workshop3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-2021/m3/00_workshops/03_workshop3/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s it In our last workshop we will be wrapping up the semester with some advanced applications, tooling and dicussion about the semester project. We will cover following approaches (tutrial / demos - some variation between R &amp;amp; Python):
SBERT - sentence embedding Autoencoders (for anomaly detection) Text classification with Fast.ai and Transformers We will also demonstrate how to create and host portfolios as static sites on Github Pages.</description></item></channel></rss>